so I'm going to do a video about neim uh
many of you will be very surprised to
hear that I am a neim user ya now and
all of my streams are on neum uh which I
absolutely love for lots of reasons that
I'll demonstrate and I'll talk about but
in order to this is also an apology
video so before we get into it the first
thing I want to say specifically to te
and to primagen is that I am sorry I am
sorry that I didn't fully understand
neovim before I chose to not use it I
could have been using it all this time
and there's some really fundamental
things that I was wrong about that would
have allowed me to use in fact I made a
video and I got 4,000 views about neovim
not following Progressive enhancement
the design technique of progressive
enhancement I was wrong about that I
immediately deleted the video like
within within once I found out that
three lines of a knit config is enough
to use my existing vmrc the same bmrc
that I used for vim and VI and nvi and
yes I'm one of the two people to quote
Prime who uses VI yeah add my two to the
thou tens of thousands of other people
who don't make YouTube videos who use VI
every day to do their job and this is
this is so this is both an a why video
why did I not like it originally going
and wanting to like it this is a poite I
have and two I'm sorry I'm sorry to the
neomen project in fact I am I was wrong
I was wrong about many things and one of
the biggest things I I I poke fun at Lua
all the time it's not that I don't like
it so this video is going to be long but
if if you if you just want the summary
that's at the beginning if you want to
see all the reasons and the sorted
history and how how I came to be where I
am now and how I became a neam user
today I want you to watch the whole
video and it's going to we're going to
take it back and we're going to do it in
story form okay so it might be a 10 15
minute video but I I need to do this
because I don't want people to get the
wrong impression and when they ask me
about neim and they say I thought you
hated neim I want to have a video that I
can point to so they can look at okay so
way back when you can tell by the
numbers on these zast on these knowledge
note entries these note entries that
that which when they were done there's
no dates in my system that I might made
but and and you can see that the oldest
of the of them
482 was an honest question it was an
honest question why should you not use
neoen and then you can see just from
this just from the titles of my zle cast
entries you can see how it kind of got
by the numbers you can kind of see how I
got kind of mad I got kind of mad and
kind of hateful and kind of frustrated
and every time that happens it's almost
usually in defense of my choices because
what happens is as a live streamer and a
YouTuber you know this right people
would wal into my streams in the middle
of a coding session without even
bothering to ask what was going on and
then they would say why are you using
viim instead of neovim you're stupid and
and you don't believe me I can show you
time I wish I clipped them all people
would come in and and they would say
you're such an idiot for not using Neo
and they would would attack me for not
using it I mean how stupid is that I
mean I know Prim and te would agree with
it that that's not the proper behavior
but just like rust same thing I got
death threats over us people they they
get trendy they get cultish they get
dogmatic and and because they're
Anonymous they feel like they can talk
[__] about stuff all the time well I'm
not Anonymous so I can talk
[__] as long as I justify the [__] and
tell you why so listen let me tell you
what I started with and why I started
out like there's other videos of this
you want to go back and see fat bearded
rob you can go read you can go watch the
other videos and there's a few that are
pretty angry but let's let's actually
open these up and go through it and do a
thing and then if somebody wants to
react to it you can so why not neim neim
is absolute [__] made by people who
should never have been created in the
first place that I that is not a
commentary on the people who made it
this is something I have to be really
careful with I am not attacking the
authors okay I can attack something an
author makes without attacking the
authors I can say the thing that you
made is [__] but that doesn't indirectly
means that I think that you are [__] or
that you're a bad person and I don't
like you this is something that I think
that the generations today that my
generation grew up with and I think that
the generations today don't fully
understand this is the basis of the
toxicity and Prime actually talked about
in one of his videos recently he's
trying to get his head around what is
the appropriate you know argument and
dialogue over there because it gets
pretty I mean they're calling each other
[__] brze and back burst and all kinds
of stuff it's like and he literally
called it out when do you know when this
is like healthy you know uh Exchange in
terms of like IRC Linux you know news
groups versus um you know the the um you
know the more healthy exchanges that you
see among the millennial and the genz
generation which by the way I think is a
good thing Tor waldis has checked
himself into uh to anger therapy to deal
with it I mean this you read some of the
stuff he says it's not acceptable for
any human being to speak to another
human being like that let alone one of
your peer Colonel
developers I mean you you would have to
be in my in my way of thinking you would
have to be the kind of you'd have to be
drinking beers the other with your arm
around him and say that's completely
stupid Mr Rob you're a [__] and I've
had people that I helped Mentor tell me
that to my face because because that was
okay and you know Prime made an
absolutely fantastic conclusion he goes
culture starts at the top and he is so
right and and I want to I really really
really want to live that tenant I want
to live that tenant and if and if
there's something you can tell from my
times from when I had ancient drama with
pre not even we're bringing up four or
five years ago and to my time today if
you go look at my streams then and my
streams now the culture of my the
culture of my community my live
streaming community and my community in
general has been positive right and
quite frankly my in-person school the
culture was always very positive we
would tease each other and we would poke
each other and we say that's totally
stupid but we didn't mean it and we
could tell because we could communicate
but but as soon as the whole thing went
online now you're screwed right because
not everybody's making a video where you
can hear the the twinge in the voice
right or you know I I'm always being
defensive and overreactive to to stuff
that gets typed in my chat because
somebody might be giving me a hard time
there's no way for me to know I didn't
know what a Kappa even was when I first
started so I get all and I'm already my
wife will tell you I'm already very
defensive about everything so given that
climate you know it's not okay to talk I
think it's okay to talk [__] people have
talked [__] about my things that I've
made a lot and I've talked about this
before Chris Nova the red lakeer Chris
Nova didn't talk [__] but she said
you're doing this I don't think this is
a good way to do this and I end up
changing because because somebody gave
me the feedback all right so the reason
this I want people to understand that
when I first wrote the blog post why not
neim and and I linked to it um that it
was it was because of very solid reasons
it was because I actually tried it like
should I use this new thing that
everybody's using is VI going to be okay
and and I actually just like Russ I had
to come to the conclusion that it was a
bad idea and um here it is positive
things about NE that's the new one I
just wrote um I'm actually trying to
find I broke the whole thing down and
I'm trying to find the
breakdowns uh why not neim all right
there it
is I think this is uh I think anyway so
um actually it's not even we're talking
about it let me let me summarize the
main points I I there were like there
was a video there was a video I made and
there was a write up I made and there
was like Pro probably 10 or 15 specific
points that I didn't like about neam um
and they it's not even really important
I mean they ripped out Pearl support and
then they had it back they took out the
smile for God's sake I mean why would
they do they they were incompatible they
made their V Mar and VRC completely
incompatible uh which isn't completely
true it might have been when I tried to
run it back then it didn't work um and I
mean there's a lot of things about the
the neim culture that really rubbed me
the wrong way they weren't giving Braum
credit they were calling their
conferences Vim without even asking him
um and and I found out later that they
eventually approached him and they got
him on board with it and everything so
my but primarily my critique was why and
I was tired of defending myself and a
lot I started saying things like this I
would say people would say why aren't
you using neoen that's kind of stupid
you're not using it's like you're
throwing away I had some I had one
person say hey we can't it's in the
comments somewhere it's like it's like
you know old people are going to you
know we can't save you from being an old
person who doesn't adopt new ideas you
know we can't save you from that and
they're like they were attacking my
ability to to to process new things when
I have been predicting new technologies
and new things for the last for
successfully for 25 years I was the
first person coding go on Twitch go
count how many people are coding go on
Twitch now okay so it's not like that
I'm not an early adopter or that I don't
believe in trending things it's just I
want to know if it's got weight or if
it's a trend and I'm really good at
distinguishing the difference um I have
been my life work has been has been
proven that so so when I saw Neen my
first thing is like why and so people
are saying why aren't you using NE I'm
like why are you using it nine times out
of 10 guess what the answer was I want
to use Lua plugins I'm like why are you
using Lua
plugins and there well I want to be able
to run this thing here or I want to be
able to do this other thing here and I
was like
okay but you can already do that right
you know that and they're like no I
didn't know that I said do you know
about the do you know about the do you
know about the uh do you know about the
um filter command they're like no what's
that why would I use that they they
literally didn't know Vim they didn't
know it they hadn't fully learned Bim
because neovim had taught them to all
these other things and and to do things
a different way and and it frustrated me
and made me angry I was like well why
would you do that why would you hand
away why would you throw away me you
know finger memory compatibility on any
system that's running viim as opposed to
having to install neim and then one of
the stories came up let me show you one
so one of the stories came up uh it's
it's it's Ken uh it's K
497 and this one really kind of hit at
home for me uh and and this is kind of
rough to read but I'm going to read
anyway NB gets re forom my Zell and Neo
in production uh you can take your Neo
viim plugins to your pretty little om my
G shell colors into production
containers sometimes you'll be lucky to
have the
not been I made a video about this is VI
not V and not V uh and and and and an
actual shell that isn't busy box which
is a multic call app not a shell the
following is based on actual events
names have been changed to protected
guilty belows the chat that happens
today in a live stream while I while
while I hold nothing personally against
the people who participated I'm not
sugarcoating this it has to be called
out this will save people the hassle of
either getting fired or reamed a new
thing for having senior team members and
this is seriously I know I'm sounding
like angry and hating here but it's
actually in defense of people who are
trying to break into the industry
particularly in Ops and not particularly
SE for software development right I said
this is why this is why I go to such
great links to help people understand
that all this stuff other streamers on
YouTubers do is not professional this is
this is the height of me getting really
pissed off and I got dark I got dark and
angry and but I'm I'm not hiding it from
you because I'm telling you that my
opinion on this has totally changed I'm
going to delete this after this but I
want you to see it before I do because I
want you to see that you know even you
can you should always be willing to
change your mind even when presented
with new evidence and so it says here I
said and and this this this here is a
direct attack on the primagen and and I
admit it I didn't use the name and I'm
super embarrassed to show this and put
this in a video but I'm owning it and
I'm and I'm going to say apology to
Prime again I am apologizing to Prime
and I'm apologizing to te because I was
so angry about this happening and being
so frustrated that I took it out on them
and I I started to attack their skills
at homm which is totally wrong totally
wrong even in just it's not okay so so
there's not even there there's not even
on on a system like that you're not
going to have Zell you're not going to
have neim OPM these other technology
YouTubers and streamers who love to be
seen and have cutesy icons and cutcenes
and keyboard cameras and bounce around
on bouncy
balls and and now I just think it's cute
honestly now I just think it's cute and
I've been totally silly I've actually
been clipped you know taping my nipples
when I was drunk I I get it okay it's
streaming it's a different thing so I
got nothing against people who do that I
think it's kind of cute uh perpetually
hyp casting and League of leg like a
like a League of Legends game never say
only do this on your system never
production they they never say that and
so the noobs get stuck with their sticky
fly strip stream and coming away God
this is horrible coming away with
seriously bad ideas about how Enterprise
technology works these people have never
even heard the term change management in
their lives they don't know or care
about 49 up time and they are reasons
the bfh became a thing if you don't know
what BH is it stands for it stands for
bastard operator from hell and that's
what I would normally be classified in
if I was in charge of everything and I
would say no we can't have that you
can't have that you know and this is
kind of a thing so let's keep going so
these so these noobs think that adding
pretty things to the production will
help their Pro their proactive uh
contribution then you get this by the
way this has nothing to do with being a
boomer it's that's a I call call me a
boomer because I use VI or I use them is
pretty damn agist and it's kind of a
dick move honestly I mean really you
know I there's people that are way
younger than me there's people in their
20s at my at my work who tell me all the
time that I am being too Progressive in
my use of some of the Neo imp like that
so they're like really and these are
these are people in their 20s okay so
this has nothing to do with age um this
is what they said hello uh new busy day
senior op de got really mad with me L
hello made me uninstall my Zell op the
production instances yeah uh y'all use
that I I use I just use vanilla
terminals uh we shop an autoc CD uh this
is this is somebody in the chat saying
this he said we didn't need that in
production and I think it improves The
Experience my machine my rules uh won't
let me do neoen plugins either so I
emailed his boss we'll see what he says
did he say why he said that he didn't
want all the bloat on the production
system but it gets better he's not a
boom he's just A's he's just a boomer
why did who who did not want that my
senior devops manager threaten to take
away my production access did he seem
afraid of your Wizardry skills well no
not the lizard just trying to make
things better okay so I'm going to
actually inject another story that just
happened this week this week and the
person's actually in the chat right now
so don't don't say anything if you if
you want to be anonymous okay there's a
person in my chat who has been who has
been saying uh please please if whoever
it is please don't confirm this because
this is going to go on YouTube so
there's somebody in my chat right now
who has to defend themselves for using
VI or using even Vim in on a in a
development environment and they're
being told and I quote VSS code is the
only safe way to write code you make
more mistakes with VI and Bim and this
is actually one of those places where in
addition to my apologies Prime and to te
about getting kind of personal and silly
and in my attack there I'm gonna I I can
actually say thank God we agree that Vim
is awesome okay we agree that Vim is
awesome and we should be focusing on
that instead of on our our our stupid
religious differences and this whole
catastrophe in the rust kernel right now
and all the toxicity that's been
elevated by that has really brought home
to me how important it is particularly
with the election right now in a week
that we need to focus on what we agree
on and what not necessarily what we
disagree on we can we can disagree it
depends on obviously the scale of the
thing that you're disagreeing about um
but that's what I think we should do and
so what I'm trying to say here is that
I I think the prime would think that
that comment about vs code being less
error prone than Vim is rather silly
it's a rather silly thing and I told him
I told him Point Blank I said I said you
should just quit and I said and he
laughed and I I found out later that he
had headphones on but his team was right
around him when he asked the question he
broke out and laugh her and I said no
really seriously if if a team actually
is that clueless then your only hope is
to go find another team and by the way
thank God for the team I'm on currently
they regularly remind me that I'm
getting too Progressive which is so cool
it's so cool my team is so awesome I
love it if you find a good team it is
worth tens of thousands of dollars to
have a good team okay not just because
they're clueless uh they're they're
clued in but also because they're nice
and they're fun to work with and they're
they're they're always at a question
mark onto the end of their statements as
if there's something they could always
be learned by there which by the way is
a great tip if you if you want to
actually get farther in life instead of
staying declaring everything when
somebody says something in the chat or
something put a question mark on it just
change the period to a question mark all
it's doing is saying right right am I am
I wrong on this and then it's opening up
the possibility for a conversation so
you don't look like you're you're you're
wagging your finger at them which I have
done and do all the time so you know
speaking to myself here think about it
why do you think something as minimal as
busy box or Alpine is the most popular
image for containers there's a reason
now imagine throwing all those
optimizations uh because you're a noob
who doesn't know how to Blind Mount
volumes and other stuff due to
development work on them locally instead
you are going to bloat the entire base
image into production seriously you put
that stuff you you pull that stuff with
me and it would be the first and only
warning most most would fire you on the
spot for that level of absolute
unprofessional clueless it's not
particularly true it's just I was really
angry uh hate me if you want but you
might as well just keep
uh keep the job a little longer okay I
want you to watch this because I'm going
to do it in front of you I am deleting
this I no longer think any of that okay
I was angry I was angry I was like
really angry because I as you saw I was
defending myself and people in my
community were having to defend
themselves and continue to have to
defend themselves for even using the
terminal I was using the terminal and
there was a a Linux does tech there was
a Linux does Tech stream and I was one
of the ones in there and actually they
actually put my stream on while I was
writing a Blog response and their people
were saying only old Boomers use the
terminal that's what they were saying
that's what they were saying I've seen
this this I've seen this comment all
over the Internet guess what guys if you
don't use the terminal you can't have a
job in Tech in certain areas of
technology I don't know where this is
coming from but it's wrong and and thank
God te uh you know the prime priment um
you know lowlevel all of them they all
agree they all agree that you need
terminal skills thank God thank God we
don't have a disagreement on that um
just uh okay just a joke yes um V I
actually used vs code for a year you can
go watch that I don't think vs code is
lame that's not what I'm saying I am not
saying vs code is lame I am saying that
vs code is no likely to cause errors or
less likely to cause errors than other
stuff right uh okay so so anyway you can
see how this is going um let's let's go
ahead let's do another another neim
thing so so there we go and as you can
see so the why not neim that was kind of
the beginning of it um and let's
actually we're going to delete this one
too there is a video uh up there for
that and uh I I went through all the
baselines and stuff like that uh again
I'm just going to summarize the biggest
complaint I had against neim was that if
you burned neim stuff into your fingers
and you didn't have neim on a system you
were done if you got on another system
and the people who are pushing neam are
programmers usually who are on a laptop
they never go they never leave the
laptop and they're they have a lot in
common I this is why I call it an IDE
even though the goals say we are not an
IDE on the nean project I there's
another name I think TJ has for it which
is very legitimate I really like it uh I
can't remember it right now though it's
it's not it's I think it's a personal
development environment I think the word
and and that's a great way to think of
Neo neim is like emac this the core
developers politics and other things
they use emac you know astronomy people
academics they love emx they can make it
they can make it however they want they
can use list and it's big it can deal
with larger code bases much better than
than than Bim or neim especially much
more better than Bim even though you
know the the C kernel was written in VI
yeah the C the Unix kernel was
originally developed in VI period VI
stands for by the way visual mode of Ed
and Ed is the original Linux editor it
still is and that hasn't changed does
that mean you should learn it I think
you should do you have to it's up to you
if you're going to be a programmer all
day and cod all day fine but why why
make yourself in why why make your
skills incompatible on a system that
only has VI when you don't really have
to right and then you know you can
progressively add skills as you have
them just like you can progressively
detect uh abilities in your vmrc which
was the key for me understanding and
loving neoy and and I'm going to take a
little side break here to show you what
I mean by that so my Bim RC which does
not get noticed by neim and that sent me
off I was like you know it took nothing
for them to just look to see if there's
an EO a VRC there and load it and and
then I was I was really mad I was like
why didn't you do that that that's kind
of being you're kind of being dicks
about it you could have just loaded it
right and the answer is they're like
well we can't be sure that you want to
use that right so the solution I'll show
you so here here's my neovim stuff in it
right so my bmrc will now run my VRC
will run on anything it'll run on an a
machine with only VI it'll run on Alpine
it'll run on anything that's got any of
it why because we have this condition
here that detects whether L was a thing
right and this like tells it it's not a
thing and by the way this stuff right
here if for some reason it weren't
compatible guess where it can go yeah
you probably guessed already right so do
config all the neoen people are laughing
at me right now and yeah I'm having fun
learning something new but so here we go
in it. Bim this is all it takes if I if
somebody all all I ever needed to hear
from all the people that instead of
spending time hating on me for not
liking NE all they had to do was show me
this if they had showed me this I would
have been gold golden I would have been
golden and I would have said okay fine
if you if you have Bim on your system my
Bim will get used if you have if you
have neovim this will get used let me
show you how to do this I'm going to
make a another video about this but but
if you here's here's how you decide so
people say all the time why are you
typing VI I'm typing VI for one very
obvious easy reason I was raised on VI
that's what my fingers type they don't
type them they never have so I've always
have VI and bi has always been the
aliens for them and that's been the case
for every version of Linux has ever
existed so so and but I've actually used
this advantage to my advantage in one
additional way in my bash RC which
actually might become a Zell RC at
someday we're going to do a universal RC
and with hard links and I'll show you
that stay tuned to see that um because
now that I know some things about Zell
namely bash completion is supported by
Zell if you add a couple functions I'm
kind of down with looking at that too I
know what's happening in this universe
Rob has lost his mind right so so here
we go here we go here's here's where we
can look at the Vim thing
right so where is my
Bim uh Bim is VI vi-r I don't know why
they removed vi from uh from that's you
know what I wonder if that works I I
think one of my complaints I don't think
they
um I don't think they I think they took
view out of them of NE nope they didn't
it doesn't look like they did I don't
know I I don't know if they did at one
point I thought they they took it out
and I maybe I was wrong on that I don't
know anyway so here here's my VI my VI
is actually command now uh and I'm
trying to find it I don't think it's I
think it's a function instead of an
alias it might actually be a a where
where is it it's not Alias well here we
go type VI so V VI is Alias to envm okay
but it VI is Alias to envm dynamically
and that's what I wanted to show you so
envm there we go have envm so by default
so this is this is a progress this is
Progressive enhancement so my bash RC
says
okay number one do we have VI I've
already mounted you know VI VRC and I
can use it as V RC or xrc if I need to
which is the original name um and uh and
so then we have Bim so it says if I have
Bim on here then set thebi Alias to vim
and set my Editor to Vim if I have
neovim let's like take it up a notch
right Progressive enhancement that's
what a pwa the P pwa stands for
Progressive enhancement we take it up a
not right I have JavaScript support okay
let's use JavaScript and you know nbim
support alas VI equals nbim and then it
uses nbim this little thing have is no
something I added yeah I don't think uh
is this have GD yeah there we go have is
just a type check it just checks the
type yep it it just sees if it exists
and if it doesn't exist it goes for it
and that the reason I have it as a type
check is because if it's an alias a
function or executable of any kind it'll
it'll it'll catch it which won't catch
that so that's why I'm using type
command a lot of people don't know about
the distinction between Type between
Type command and uh which and I I think
it's super important you do by the way
this I'm going to take this opportunity
to plug skill stack beginner boost
November 3rd so we're going to do it
we're going to kick off another one um
which is kind of weird timing but anyway
so so that that I just wanted to show
you how how I got using NE and that was
the thing that saved it so let's
actually go back and start deleting out
more um I'm going to go delete some more
uh some more zets without with regard to
Neo that I no longer believe in um so uh
Neo 5 comes out further destroying
skills so this is pretty critical again
I'm owning how critical I was and the
way that I was critical and I'm
apologizing so I'm sort of a confession
here um so hyperextensibility Vim text
editor so hyperextensible right
hyperextensible Vim text editor is kind
of an oxymoron to a guy like me like
it's it's an editor right why the hell
do you need to extend it I mean you see
what I'm saying I mean that's that's how
people like me think about it and I'm
not just talking about old people um
kick up November third well we're going
to re we're going to regroup but this
November 3rd yeah okay so I can't I
can't I can't leave without commenting
on how wrong that is and yet it is a tag
line for all up all new them if you an
just the word and grammar choices you
get a very accurate idea of absolute
clueless ofan
project this again I still think that
there were many things that okay when I
say clueless I was clu cluess about
something and I'm going to admit it what
I was clueless about was the mission of
the neim project the Mi and they still
say that they're not an IDE if somebody
had explained to me and this is kind of
why I'm saying this because if you're a
newent person and I'm speaking to all of
you if you're a neim person and you love
it and it's changed your life don't just
say Neo is awesome use it because I do
why are you not you're stupid don't
start with conclusions start with
explanations and say neovim is a great
uh replacement or an editor or you know
for people who like them who want to
edit powerfully on the same computer who
don't have to be productive on multiple
computers and it used to be that I
thought that it was an either or
scenario you either had to use neim
right and and and convert your entire
vmrc into L which was wrong if I had if
I had done even a minimal amount of
research on that I would have known that
and I didn't I never I never I was too
caught up in the dogma of neim which
still exists by the way which also
doesn't have an official production
releasee yet which is also a thing right
um and and so and the second part of
this is you know that I I didn't get
that they were making they were Bim Bim
is an editor for programmers at the end
of the day that's what it is it's a and
to use to quote te if I remember right a
a pro personal development environment
and when you put the word development in
there that means it's for software
development as soon as you do that it's
it's not it's not a I'm coding Bim what
do you don't like about Bim right it's
like for old people or something no I
know but like if you say I don't like
Bim because it's for old people I I hope
I know you're kidding but I hope people
don't actually say that because you
really don't sound very intelligent when
you say that you just don't and anybody
in operations or the security field uh
or God most of the academics in the
world they it's like saying only old
people use the terminal right people
start with Bim there's nothing wrong
with starting with b and I suggest that
you actually learn Ed VI viim and then
neim that's my progression that's what I
think you should learn and we're going
to get to the things I love about neovim
at the end of the video so please stay
tuned at the end of the video I'm going
to give you the list of the things I
absolutely adore about neovim that have
really turned me into a solid advocate
for it and and I want the old folks out
there you know who you are the people
that are holding on that are holding on
to VI and Vim and I'm looking at you
Dennis last miles and all the other
people you know they're they people that
you know there are people there are
commans like that who say things like
color color is juvenile that's a direct
quote from Rob Pike who made go and I
don't agree with them those those people
also need to listen because they need to
open their minds as well and they need
to consider these other Alternatives as
Progressive enhancements to what they
have available on the system okay so why
is Bim the only word not capitalized the
authors c not pay attention this is
stupid I don't know why I even had that
in there get that out of there get that
out of there that's totally stupid um I
do not think the word means what you
think it means medical definition of
hyperextensible means having the
capacity to be hyperextended or
stretched to a greater degree than
normal this is me being a pedantic
[__] because honestly I was like
annoyed and no stupid in yoga why would
I do no no neo is dangerous for
beginners and I stand by this okay I
stand by this criticism and I really
want to help people understand what I
mean by this because people people
thrust neovim particularly the pre
preconfigured people thrust the
preconfigured neovim that doesn't have a
single line of MRC in it and it's all
Lua on newbies and I think that is a
mistake I think that is a fundamental
mistake and that it will do them wrong
the only time I feel like that would
ever be appropriate is if the person
pushing neovim has had a heart-to-heart
with the individual they're talking
about perhaps in a mentor capacity and
they have said very clearly all I ever
want to do is develop software
because otherwise there is nothing wrong
with learning enough vimrc to be
productive on a system that only has
viim you follow me right what's what
what is it going to hurt well they have
to learn neoy they really don't they
don't right they could look for some old
fart like me and get a vmrc that has
nbim in it as well and now they can use
that for neim now they have a really
great start using using Bim and they can
run as run freed writing plugins in Lu
which I'm going to write next month my
own plugin that's right I'm going to do
it because there are reasons to write it
and we're going to get to the positives
about neam and the single biggest reason
to use neam is Lua Beyond any of the
other trending reasons that is the
single biggest reason to use it and
we'll get more to that later and so so
this thing I I still stand by my
critique of neoen being dangerous for
users because people that push neovim
don't they they they would be happy if
the person that they're talking to never
used Bim in their life and they never
even looked at bmrc syntax and quite
frankly it sucks ass I hate it I hate
bmrc I I hate that whole Bim script
syntax I always have I always hated I
never really fully learned it I've
written all kinds of stuff in it but
I've always it's horrible it's
absolutely just it's not designed to do
anything really useful it needed to die
a long time ago and one of the reasons
I'm pushing for neim so hard is because
I want to see it die I would love to see
a production listen quote me on this I
would love to see a production version
of neovim De veloped and deployed into
the Enterprise so it's in the standard
AP repositories and can take the place
of VI for people who wanted to get it on
their systems as of this moment you it's
not it's not production ready I use it
but it's not it doesn't even have a 1.0
yet on it so so to that end I am making
a video here apologizing and saying hey
I am here with you neim I will help you
as best I can okay and I'm I'm sorry for
being an [__] so so Unix so again but
but please please understand the person
that you're trying to push neim on
understand what their needs are you know
and and by the way the editor for them
if they're trying to be a Linux
contributor they might actually want to
be an emac user if they want to work in
in Academia particularly in um in the
area of AST astronomy they they might
want to pick up emac right because you
know there's a lot of stuff written on
the point is seek to understand what the
person is going to try to do before you
tell them what to do because you like
your thing that's that's all I'm asking
and and so that I've seen people push
their favorite thing without actually
caring about the person that ask the
question all the time and and that that
pisses me off it does it makes me angry
because that's it's narcissistic and
self aggrandizing and and it's more of a
flex than it is anything you don't give
a [__] about the person you're trying to
help and that's strong language but I've
seen it I've seen that happen and more
reasons I still haven't moved over but I
I still have my original Point too
evaluation oh hey there's the link okay
let's actually go go add the link and
then I going to delete this link as well
all right so um again after this video
this stuff will no longer exist so this
is the only evidence that I ever did all
this stuff uh to Neo or not to
Neo uh an honest question but no no hell
no this was when I first started this is
the one I mentioned ear in the video NM
which uses mm command is unfortunately
popular replacement for Rim provides no
additional value for most users can
actually harm your Vim learning Neo's
most significant failure is not
technical at all neovim design team has
demonstrated complete lack of
understanding of core values
propositioning uh as well a total disar
disregard for the fundamental unic
philosophy this is this is a people who
don't even know the filter command there
are very core people on the neovim you
know project who never even knew the
filter command
existed okay there's also people who
have been promoting neovim who have been
calling Vim who have been calling vi v
or VI and I'm and I joke with them about
that but you know so here's the
advantage that people usually present
when they ask
uh they include documented by neam
project
itself um the disadvantages better
configuration neam looks at xtg for comp
pict this is cool but this is kind of a
this is as I said it's kind of a dick
move there's really no reason they
couldn't have just read mmrc where it
was at and then people like me it just
would have worked and we wouldn't have
cared and we probably would have tried
it more we didn't know we had to add
those three lines right and and this is
me saying I don't know how to make it
work I'm not going to copy the vimrc to
some other location that's totally
stupid I'm not going to create an extra
Sim link just because you want to be a
dick about it right so I got around that
one that was the most important one
better defaults I don't agree with this
um the syntax is pretty good um I well
we're going to get into the positive
things later multiple API and plugin
support Bim has a well documented
plug-in thing uh I said that's fine but
that means they haven't been using pul
shell integration for extensibility
because they don't know what filter
commands are have a clear internal API
uh think about wh versus ex changing
features a single feature as a change is
ridiculously relevant is uh let's see
what is what is even worse is that new
has actually corrupted the expected
behavior of the current VI and Bim
options and X commands this I actually
made a video really complaining about
and I deleted it they don't they they
throw errors and apparently there's some
way to stop it from throwing errors um
but I I think uh the best way to do that
is to just you know put those under if
if enim and if not then so those those
command options won't get thrown um I do
think it's dangerous and stupid um so
the fact that their Neo MC does has
things you can't have in there uh is it
it it it craps out on on certain things
that are supported by Legacy bi uh
missing legac featur they ripped the
Pearl support out I I actually recently
found there's Pearl support in envm
again I don't know why they added it
back but it's definitely back um and
then remove features so they remove view
which I really I'm really sad that they
removed view view view is the synonym
that opens up um neovim I mean viim in
readon mode so you can't make a change
it's actually the standard way that the
password file or or sudu viu opens
because it wants to do it read only
there is a way to do this with nbim but
you have to add a specific flag uh so if
you're going to do this is a relatively
minor thing but you have to add you'd
have to add a function or something
called View and then you'd have to pass
the command properly if it's neim you'd
have to detect if it's neim and then
send the right thing and I'm going to
put that in my my Universal RC file uh
because I'm okay with that but that is
still a problem uh you can't log out you
can't run a shell from the thing I never
really cared about that but still um uh
and they remov smile for some reason
actually did they add that back let's
see if they actually added it back I I
doubt very seriously they did um I don't
I don't think they did V
Tempo all right so smile wait wrong
thing did they add
smile did they smile no they added smile
back they added smile
back that's cool you can't read it but
that's cool they added how why would
they why would they pull it and then add
it back I don't understand that at
all I I really don't they when I went
through the source code they ripped it
out it was totally out I wonder if they
just hadn't ported it over yet I bet
that was it I feel bad for calling that
out you know what you know what that is
I I think I know the reason for that I'm
going to give them other thing you know
this goes without saying but um give
people the benefit of the doubt my
friends and I failed I failed on this
part let me let me show you another way
I failed okay um yeah so I in in this
write up I assumed nefarious intent that
they actually like said we hate those
Boomers we're going to take out their
their Pearl we're going to take away
their Pearl from them and we're going to
we're going to make we're going to
ignore their mrc's because they need to
put it in the right place cuz they're
too old androgyny and we hate them and
and oh my God we're going to take out
the they were going to take out the
smile just to piss him off that's not at
all what happened that's not at all what
happened you know what happened what the
benefit of the doubt and I'm God I feel
so stupid at realizing this now looking
back at how I my how I acted and behaved
what they probably did is now that I
know that it's Alpha software it's never
had an official production release that
what what is more likely the case and
I'm pretty sure anybody would confirm
this is they waited on the least
important functions to add those later
so they were busy dealing with other
bugs and things that were more
significant before they added back full
compatibility because they've been
pushing pull compatibility all along and
I'm like it's not FY compatible and
they're like well yeah but we're working
on it okay so maybe the smile command
can wait until we get oh I don't know
all of the syntax is
supported rob you see what I'm saying so
if I had if I had been more agreeable
and if I had been willing to give them
more benefit of the doubt in that case
then I could have avoided um the thing
my my comments on neovim led to the
drama the the really massive drama
between prime and I and I don't want to
even get in it ended up getting me all
kinds of this I don't want to even get
into it but it was ugly it was ugly on
all the sides I got cancelled all over
and it wasn't worth it and and I'm I'm
not apologizing to get back in the good
graces of anybody I give a [__] uh but
and as you know um you know I regularly
rate Prime and and I have no hard
feelings towards any of them I this is
me apologizing legitimately but I'm not
doing it because I I I want to buy
credit with somebody I'm doing it
because it's the right thing to do when
you find out that you were wrong on
something own it and frankly tell people
about it because maybe somebody else has
made the same mistake as you and they
can walk with you in your steps I
changed my opinion on things back and
forth so often get lab GitHub get get
lab GitHub that I've got a nickname with
my people that I've Mentor thousands of
people and their their nickname for me
is flip-flop rob you know why because
every time I get new information I
change my opinion and in the tech world
that might be daily right and and I I
don't I don't think that's a bad thing
should I have done a little bit more
research every time yeah but you don't
have time to do that level of research
you've got to try things you know what
I'm saying um and so so so here we are
yes just say no more accessible teams
okay so let me let me finish up my
review I know I told you this was going
to be a long video but I want to be
thorough because there this video is
going to go viral and I don't I I don't
want it to go viral but it is because
because there's going to be a lot of
people that's going to create the Neo
versus Vim thing all over again and and
I I'm not again I'm not pumping the
views I'm doing the right thing I'm
using neovim I'm owning how I was an
[__] and I'm telling them I'm sorry
all right so more accessible team just
yeah just no no one ever believe that
for a second if anything the Bim team is
simply more capable and Discerning than
neim team I don't I don't agree with
that at all anymore um did Braum and the
Gang have more experience than the neim
team yes they definitely did were they
more
capable who knows I don't I'm not in a
position to evaluate that that was
totally out of bounds and not a fair
critique um external plugins in a
separate process I think this is kind of
crazy this might be true but again is
irrelevant okay so neim started
primarily because the people that wanted
to get things in a Bim couldn't get it
and that that I have read
and they couldn't get their stuff into
BM because the Vim project was pushing
back one of the things they wanted to
get in was to get concurrency so at the
time you know waiting around for an LSP
was impossible you would have to wait
forever now every time I open up a go
program let me show you not my Emojis
let me show you every time you open up a
go program this is actually a really
important thing so any every time you
open a go program up it kicks off an LSP
you see down at the bottom and depending
on how large the package
is that a um strong opinions weekly held
weekly held that's the that's the saying
strong opinions weakly held loosely held
I actually changed mine to weekly we k l
y because I change my opinion all the
time so anyway the the point of it is in
the old Vim in the old Vim when you open
this right here you'd have to sit around
and wait for the LSP to actually run
until you could even do any editing and
there was no concurrent updating of the
LSP in the background there were no it
wasn't there was no support for currency
in B at all and the neoen I think the I
I could be wrong in this but I think the
neoen Project's primary complaint was
that that didn't exist and so they
forked it they said we're going to do
our own thing and they went off on with
their with their ball and they did their
own thing and they did a great job I
mean honestly they did and they got
concurrency and guess what they
pressured Vim into doing the same thing
right uhhuh in fact Vim Vim the Vim
project has even recently released a
whole new version of inscript because
again pressure on how easy it is to
write the code for configuration so it
it's not bad to have two attempts at a
thing as long as you present it that way
it's like another option make sure you
understand all your options here's what
we're doing I actually think that's good
I I wish that starlink had a better
competitor in Amazon I wish they' get
their [__] together because then that
would push both of them to be better
that's not a bad thing that's not a bad
thing um and Bim yeah bimm is totally
trying to catch up to neam and quite
frankly the rust the I have that same
thing could happen in the rust Community
if rust makes a Linux compatible kernel
and they all rust people who are you
know on board and they're not fighting
against people over stupid things like
has recently happened who knows they
might actually catch up too you know and
and that's not a bad thing a lot of
these things have to be Rewritten arm
versus Intel you know chip architecture
sometimes maintaining the backward
compatibility with all the other stuff
is just too hard I tried to update Cobra
and and get rid of some stuff and is
like no this stuff is crap and there's
stuff in there that I don't want like
get Ops I want to do my own thing start
a bonsai starting your own thing is not
a bad thing whether it be alacrity or
whatever you know and and that that's
not what I'm that's that's not the
criticism I'm making so so external so
process external processes yes better
support for laity lity is amazing um but
that's a separate issue that should
never have been listed as neim issue
gives Bim healthy competition this is
true and I just said it's a good thing I
still think it's a good thing um uh it
has pains okay the use of pains in Bim
is an anti-pattern and if people that
are doing it who aren't using t-
are frankly they are missing out on a
ton of opportunity I don't have to
really make the case here this is people
people who are actually like reasonable
and think through this understand that
pains offer no additional benefit to an
extra t-mo window or an extra t-mo pain
the difference is is that I can split
the pain with t-u having and I can cut
and paste between running processes and
test output which I regularly do and I
can put that into the other pain to to
to do that in Vim pains is a
pain see what I did there all right so
bug stability has been reported the neim
contains lots of bugs and stability
issues uh this is true actually hit one
this is still true I was using neim and
I I was I was letting the F bombs go for
like 20 minutes some people were here in
my stream I was letting them go for 20
minutes I had converted to neim a week
ago and in the middle I fat fingered
something and all of a sudden there I
had no syntax fting and everything was
all red in every file I opened even if I
closed the file out it was obviously a
really glaring neoen bug and I had no I
was pissed because I was in the middle
of a really fast going you know code
session I completely lost my train of
thought I couldn't I I I couldn't do
anything and the editor had just ruined
me it had totally ruined me and when
that you want to get me angry that's how
you do it and then like we were all my
whole chat went into into you know
emergency mode oh my God what can we do
to fix this so we're like looking around
like where does it even keep the state
and then we found we I some suggested
the place it's I think it's local state
or something which isn't even in the in
they make a big deal about being all xtg
config compliant yeah but on a Mac they
put the state data you know they don't
put it in the standard XG cach directory
you know where they put it local state
you know who uses that local state no
one no one uses that
location so if you're going to make a
big stink about being all official new
configuration location [__] you might
want to put it in the right place
because we couldn't find it you put your
cash in the wrong place you you made a
big thing about oh do config is the xdg
way to put it that's the new modern way
to put itl this. loal can. loal cash you
know what no it's not it's whatever is
the next you can Pig and on Apple
there's a standard Cash location you'd
know that but they don't and so we spent
20 minutes looking for the cash I know
we probably could have done a search
faster than that we didn't because I had
to find it myself I was like blah blah
BL I should have just searched and so
anyway we finally found it deleted the
cash blew out all of my neam cash which
I didn't even know it was doing caching
I had no idea no idea what it was being
written or anything it wasn't in it
wasn't you know in any other normal
place so I learned a lot about neim in
that moment and and that's fine but that
was that you know that was not standard
and it was a bug a pretty bad bug and
neim is still full of bugs and it still
hasn't got an official official release
this is still a very valid uh concern
and the reason I was going to hold off
on making this video for another month
even though I I just refused I finally
did it I was going to wait and do this
after a month went by to make make sure
that I am really you know my apology is
sincere but I I wanted to be sure that
I'm going to actually keep new of him
and I wanted to give it at least a month
before before you know if I hit another
I tell you what if I lately I've been
getting bugs that the buffers aren't
closing out and I have to refresh I have
to Glow out and reroll my script I don't
know if they're plug-in author bugs or
they other bugs but you know they're
they're they're not annoying enough for
me to stop using it and let's actually
let's take this into a positive Place
let's tell you all all the reasons that
you should use it so this is the end of
the video dude why so AR new him people
are like you know people are getting
over enging C bullet makers blah blah
blah this is just me being mean this
I've already made that point the point
is I'm sick of defending myself uh and
I'm s you know and and that's I
shouldn't have to defend myself honestly
and I think most of those people would
agree okay so so that this this this uh
this Z Caston is now gone um and uh
because I don't I don't agree with any
of that again let's uh let's keep going
I know this is a really long video but I
I don't want to do it again I just want
to do it once and be done with it so
please please bear with me um positive
things okay so uh how let's see uh how
stupid is neim for removing view let me
do that one first uh NE has been
frequently point the point of
conversations last week because I just
had a critical need to use open a bunch
of files um the absolute perfect use
case was you I want to open up a whole
bunch of files and view uh but neam team
said the option for view was unable you
can't do it you can't open because
they're stupid cuz they're so [__]
stupid that wrong mean horrible Rob he
needs to go away he needs to stop that
delete that and and again I'm I'm I'm
really sorry because there may be people
uh who have not seen how the vitriol
that I wrote about this and I'm showing
you now and maybe maybe there this is
going to drum up some old drama I really
hope not uh I'm trying to tell you I was
being an [__] and I was Dumb and I
need to get rid of it even makes the
other editors look like Stonehenge
that's an exact quote from a very
passion NE them us a word for word #
clueless um I don't agree with that at
all I don't I I don't agree I don't
agree and I think I think the aism
implication is is bad uh VI is minimal
it's more minimal than than than neim
and being minimal is not a bad thing
there's a lot of people who need minimal
that's why Bim is the standard Linux
editor on most systems neim is not and
and until and until you know they they
can come around with that uh Bim uses
cash Bim no it does not it might use
that but that's not where the state was
we had to delete do do local
dstate for it to go away and I and I was
like what the hell is this there was
like local D it was some other location
I can't even find it now but it wasn't
it wasn't D cash Bim it wasn't cash Bim
neim did I say Bim yeah I met neim uh VI
uses docash Bim I think mine
does um I think mine actually does and I
think Bim actually probably has come
around and started using the standards
um but yeah so anyway uh Nano for the
win yeah we won't even talk about Nano I
I actually made go go go do Nano say no
just say no to Nano yeah I did a whole
thing on that because Nano breaks you it
breaks your hands it breaks your fingers
it breaks your muscle memory it makes
you want to type stupid things like
control C instead of escape and not
knowing it sends an interrupt and why
that's bad um Neo ship in ring
developers okay this I I'm kind of
scared to open this one I have a feeling
I'm going to open it publicly but I'm
really scared to open it right now
because I have a feeling it's really bad
um yeah update hey look I've shaken the
hornet nest uh of useless rust and neoen
Fanboys by writing this they hate being
wrong meanwhile tons of other now and by
the way they were wrong rust the Russ
people were totally wrong and I was
right and everybody is saying Russ sucks
and and I made a video saying I was
right
uh Neo them thing on many of the things
I was right but most of them I was wrong
they hate being wrong meanwhile tons are
getting great jobs in huge companies
don't allow neop fcking Vi at all but
they really would rather Ranch in either
uh that's so unfair Rob I expect as much
from the rest uh crypto nft people but
they can spot them crypto said the same
thing I said I said crypto nft was was
for morons and it's totally stupid and
you're all going to get scammed and I
was right I'm sorry I was right and by
the way Bim has has problems too TR
using out and busy box container oh wait
you can't because you got you don't get
ne or even Bim uh yeah you pre I that
that that kind of writing just is not
needed um NE is [__] ruining new um did
I write
that I don't think I even wrote that one
please tell me that I didn't write
this who wrote this oh my God I didn't
Ru I write it I didn't write it
oh my God I didn't write that that
wasn't even me I thought that was me the
whole time I feel
better somebody else was a bigger
[__] than
me Kel
supr okay well there you
go oh no no no no no no no no that was
that was oh yeah that was somebody
posting that was some okay that was me
that was somebody posting
hey look at this man this God the [__]
in here is like if okay I'm going to
send you this link and that's the only
place I'm going to send a link all right
I'm going to send you the link and it's
the only
place okay
um that was them sending me this happens
to me all the time I make a [__] post
and they make a Reddit post about it
that's what they did with
rust and um this was actually on a
lobster a lobster page which everybody
knows rust has got problems down it's so
funny how trending it is to like hate on
Russ now I made a video about it it's I
think it's kind of funny um I don't even
hate on Russ as bad as of people are
hating on Russ now so anyway that was me
and then but but that the reason I'm
posting that is because if you want to
see how much hate came out of the people
the neim community and how much all of a
sudden I was on the defensive for not
even liking it and it wasn't because I
started out being assle if you look if
you read my very first post and I went
through it I was kind of there was a
point there it was a little personal but
the very first I don't think we should
use neim post turned into a fight and I
was getting bludgeoned and I got I
became an [__] because I was being
defensive which I do which is bad I
don't want to do that neim which uses
nbim command is unfortunately a popular
replacement of B is bad is Ru is ruining
beginner developers blah blah blah uh in
other words Vim neovim would be a
reasonable learning path but beginners
don't do that I already talked about
that my disappointment about neovim is
not personal good people some very close
to me us an advocate NE them this is
true this is absolutely true and I
actively campaign against it I [__]
hate it but hey it's it's the same for
Crypt shell currency the reason I hate
it the number one reason was because I
couldn't use my vmrc and I was wrong so
VI ne's most signicant fail is not
Technic at all NE design team has
demonstrated like I already did this one
uh here are the advantages people
usually present when why blah blah blah
uh yeah that's I already covered that
better configuration even looks like XG
home is a configuration file except for
its cash it doesn't use that it doesn't
use xdg cash home it doesn't for some
reason and still a bug unfortunately we
have all the two de of dot files but
[__] you that's this really pissed me
off because all I had to do was load my
vmrc if it existed but they said no
we're not doing that Boomer uh it still
pisses me off that they don't do that
even though it's just three lines in in
in nbim do then then in nbim whatever uh
better defaults the second best thing I
already covered all these this looks
like a a repeat uh this is this is just
a repeat of the one that I I was looking
for this earlier this is the repeat of
the of the web one that we already went
through so um I was actually looking for
that I'm glad it's gone in the game so
so there um so
there so that so
that so K neim all right so the last the
only thing left in my zcast about neovim
is now the positive things about neovim
and let's talk about that at the end of
the video so if you made it this long I
appreciate your patience and your
forgiveness so it says here um neim the
the mob mentality of neim you're more
likely to encounter uh someone using
neim today than vim and you at least are
more likely to find them on the internet
now I have a theory about that I have a
theory that the V users to to quote zor
genheimer who had to start using it
because there was no Vim on a AA system
he was forced to support because the old
people died um or you know VI as as
Prime calls it um is I I we don't have
numbers on that right it's not just old
people it's people all over doing things
that don't make YouTube videos that are
not being counted in they're not
answering stack exchange surveys and
there's no statistics there's absolutely
zero statistics so the conclusion that
there seems to be more easy more people
on Neo to collaborate with as far as we
know that only holds true for people who
are making YouTube videos or live
streaming and quite frankly people that
are making YouTube videos and live
streaming are are not the authorities on
Enterprise file editing either in
software development or you know in
operational capacity they they just
generally aren't they can share their
experience and that's fantastic and I'm
glad they do but there is just not you
know a lot of evidence about it people
drro 2 very famously switched back
between forth between vim and emac and
Vim and emx and I asked myself what is
he using it for you know editing his own
personal projects and stuff is he is he
working and what capacity is he working
what's the best tool for the job you
know it's like asking me what's your
favorite
Hammer well I like ballpen hammers but
how do you take Nails out I don't need
to take Nails out ballpen hammers suck
you see how stupid that is it's really
stupid to argue about a tool unless you
know what you're trying to do with a
tool and if you're trying to maintain a
large code base on the same laptop and
you never have to REM go onto another
system neim is absolutely ideal I I
think NE is way better than emx for that
reason why because your muscle memory is
also going to follow you into onto a
system where you're using Vim or VI or V
or or VI or whatever you want to call it
right it's still going to follow you so
neovim is actually the single best big
ass Editor to
use in that crowd terminal based editor
because why because because your skills
are going to follow you you learn emac
and again again unless you're on a
system that's got emac you're great if
you're going to go get on a multi-user
jump boox in your devops environment
like I do for my high performance
machine learning support that machine
had
vi7 Vim s on it when I got hired three
years ago we had to beg them to put a VI
newer than version 8 on and my mmrc
didn't have support for if statements in
it because it was vi7 that's how old it
was we said please please please at
least update the Vim to the latest
version
God help us if we were try to get neim
on there right or emac right so the
point is having neim is better this is
the plus Neo is better because it has a
bigger you know outspoken Community
there's a lot of people to reach out to
um my perception and I have no data
behind this is that that is not as true
for things like emac there is a huge
emac Community don't get me wrong um and
most of the Linux Colonel uh people our
emx people um but and I think emx is
fantastic I I really do there's a lot of
people who use it I I just didn't ever
learn it and I never had a desire to and
I was always kind of a security hacker
kind of person who need to have VI on
the system and so I'm perfectly content
being one of the two people who uses VI
um and and so that's why that's why I
think neim is actually a better choice
because people are there's there's a lot
of people that use it it's got a big
Community it's got a lot of energy and
Fanfare around it and you're also
picking up them skills at the same time
if you do it right if you do it right
that same critique that I made about
neovim being bad for beginners can
actually be a positive if you do it
right if you learn Vim properly and you
know then when you add neim on you just
you you if you get stuck on Bim you're
fine because you know it right it's not
like you're going to get hobbled because
you you you learn things that are neim
only or or you you become dependent on
on a Vim plugin on a Lua plugin that
that that you didn't really need to
become dependent on that you could have
done with a Unix filter had you had it
right so you don't even know what Unix
filter is right but if you learn Bim
then you know what Unix filter is you
get on system that doesn't have L
plugins your favorite stuff you can use
that so you want to sort a list you use
sort right so you want to you want to
sort a list B should we sort this list
right here we're going to use the filter
right now let's sort this list let's
sort it right here I'm going to use the
filter command so exclamation point um
so exclamation point and then um I have
to my fingers know it um right curly
bracket right and then it pass that to
sword Watch What Happens boom that's a
filter command those commands all exil
the sword things already installed on
every unic system that ever existed so
doing what I did to sort that I didn't
need a Vim plugin I didn't need a Lu
plugin I just knew how to use the filter
command and if you don't need to know if
you don't know how to use the filter
command you want to do some advanced
math right let's do some advanced math
let's do some Advanced divid blah blah
uh let's set the scale let's set the
scale equals to two all right wouldn't
it be great if we could put that math in
there bang bang uh BC
oops what did I do wrong everybody
I did it didn't do it my thing didn't
work my test didn't work I'm doing
something wrong
BC it's not doing it why is it not doing
it I don't know what's going on so
anyway you can pass this stuff to uh BC
and it should just replace it there it
goes I don't know why that other one's
not doing uh I mean anyway so you you
get the point right you can do you can
do division you can do times blah blah
you can do the thing bcor St in that was
St in this is it BC watch stud in there
it is it
works I think it was smaller than one
you're right thank you no you don't need
that you don't need any of it I'm try
trying to tell you I'm trying to show
you the thing you can do here so you
know uh plus blah blah blah okay so let
me show you so bang bang two exclamation
points replace the current line with the
output of the following command that
sends the following that sends the line
that I'm currently on to standard input
which BC takes and then replaces it with
the
output I call this viim magic and people
with filters don't know it another thing
too I use this watch uh something some
some uh header here all right another
thing no plugins no plugins people just
a script so I'm going to do bang bang H
title and it makes a title and It
Centers it and everything what is that
that I just did it's just a shell script
friends it's just just a shell script
viic VI H title it's just a shell script
it's a shell script that calculates the
width and puts it out there I didn't
need a plugin for
that right the thing that's really great
about this is I can actually use this
from the command line so I can say Echo
uh some something something here pipe
that to H title so if I wanted to I
could put it in a
script why would you limit yourself to a
Lu plugin that only works in neovim when
you can write a command that does things
that you might want to use in a script
or from the command line using the
filter or from within bi using the vi
using the filter command I don't
understand why people don't get this
most of the people when they see it
they're like oh my God I didn't know
that existed so my my my plea to you is
make sure you understand everything
about fim before you pick up neovim
because um no filter needed no I mean
the prob is but the point is is that
anything you can do on the command line
can be done here for I in uh 1 2
2034 uh do Echo I dot uh Done Right
watch that you see that I'm writing I do
this all the time I write shell this is
why you should learn bash by the way if
you learn bash you're using the bash
editor you can actually use code to
write code live
watch that to bash and there I got my
whole list right you want to do you want
to do asky art or whatever you can do
that same sort of thing I mean anything
you can run on the command line that
that accepts standard input can be run
as a filter command Okay so but yeah
sword is probably one that you could get
away with you want to put a calendar in
here Cal you know you get a calendar
right so you you I mean there's just a
million things I I have I have one that
um I have one that will actually
calculate for a table a markdown table
it will actually look at the first B of
the markdown table and put the total at
the bottom you know and it's just an
infinite there's infinite possibilities
because you're using the Unix system
you're doing it from the command line
you don't need a plugin you don't I
think plugin should be relegated to
things that are really Advanced like
like talking out to the internet or
something or or syntax highlighting I I
do think that those kind of things would
be nice to have um you you can you can
have code macros so I don't use visual
mode at all because I hate it personally
uh I use this you want to comment it use
comment like that use use CMT I mean and
look you don't have to do it the way I'm
doing it the point I'm trying to make is
that at least know what you're giving up
you know what I mean uh a little command
like this is perfect for that kind of
thing in fact I can change what commment
I want on the first line most of the
time I want to do that by the way this
allows me to do more precise selections
visual mode you have to like push a
bunch of keys you have to spam crap to
get all the way to the one you want
right uh bc- L yeah well God that's a
big one yeah I mean there's there's
there's a bunch of commands you can do
here um the point is not the point is
just make sure you understand how to use
MIM before you use Neo but then be my
guest to use me what are some things
that eim does about floating screen
window key mode so so this is actually
something that I have been using a lot
lately you see the screen key at the top
of the screen this is something that I
don't think Prime and knows about it I
think he might be interested in adding
it um he has some really he's using
screen key because he got Linux on the
desktop I stopped using Linux on the
desktop years ago for reasons that I
don't want to get into right now um I'm
using a Unix system system that's all I
tell people but you see the screen key
stuff at the top that's using something
called windar that is 100% a Neo Lua
plugin and that is not possible in vim
and I am super jazzed that I have that
people have been asking me for you know
what are you typing and by the way this
gives up the fact that I'm doing Escape
people are saying why are you using
escape and not control C because they've
been watching Prime I'm going to give
him [__] for the rest of his days until
until he tells people that using control
C is a bad idea because that sends an
interrupt and that's a bad habit to give
to beginner so I'm using control left
bracket to to generate Escape sequences
at the top rather than like go all the
way up with my pink to the Escape so
again this is not a Vim class but I
wanted to show you this uh it's what
most people use in collaborate uh and
easy to collaborate I talked about that
live display uh is far more informative
so this is absolutely true um this is
really so The Help The Help stuff the
help stuff is like way cleaner um except
for when it's not and I don't know if
you can see that wind I think there's a
bug in Wind bar and I think it actually
messes up my my uh my referencing to
stuff uh you know you still have GD if
you want to go look at the source of a
thing um so you know you want to look at
the source for this and you want to open
up did you see what I just did there I
opened up the goang source code to see
the source code of Sprint up let's go
back it be control um what is it o and
so so there so you can go so you can
like people ask how can you get around
all the files you just navigate by
jumping back and forth to the different
things you want to see the document on I
just do capital K which has been
supported in Vim since the very first
day that has been supported that is a
standard Vim thing no matter what
language you're in that is not specific
to a specific language never has been
that's not a Neo thing uh yes I have a
Vim class I do I give Vim classes in Neo
in November 3rd we're going to start up
again and we're going to go through all
the Vim stuff so um and I have done it
for many years since 2013 uh I've taught
nine-year-olds how to use them that's a
true story uh I had nine-year-olds
install Linux on her laptop by
themselves with no help no kidding so uh
ability to leave MRC where it is small
thing I'm over it uh bar bar block
cursor indicates insert mode this is
actually super cool I don't know if you
can tell but this this my zel cast is
not using neim because it's doing it's
inferring vi from different place that's
why I don't have the screen keys um but
if over here one of the things I really
like is is insert mode changes to Bar
mode that is a neoism that I love that's
a neoism it's a small thing but my god
do I love that that is such a small
thing I don't know why neim doesn't do I
mean Bim doesn't do that but it that is
an attention to detail that actually the
neim people have demonstrated and I
really love it I I love it I think that
is going to be one of many little things
that add up to be really cool let me
show you something one of the best
things of all it's called neim debug
mode and so when I actually change um
something um you see that you see okay
let me see that let me see you see how I
save that okay you see how this little
it puts this little fire over here and
in the gutter and it has this really
clean uh uh block over here the thing is
so cool about that is that this actually
this actually if there's like two or 10
things wrong with that line that little
bar grows in size and I know that that's
a small thing but that is amazing as a
developer as a developer having that
little bar not to mention it's not ugly
let me show you the same thing in Vim so
if I do the same thing in Vim I get it's
got a different Emoji right because my I
set a different Emoji in my B RC and uh
it's a different you have to set it in a
different place uh for for Neo and I
just Ed the defaults by the way that
came with the debugger but then this but
but but but the the built-in one does
this completely ugly line and and it's
kind of hard to read it's not it's not
nearly as clean is there a reason to not
use Neo or to use Neo probably not but I
tell you what when you spend 12 hours a
day staring a code it matters those
little things matter and that is one of
the positive things about neam that I
will say neovim is a much more pleasant
experience it's so far I'm I hate saying
this but neovim the neovim interaction
has been faster and that's because I
don't have an LSP running even even with
my go LSP running I'm not running an
external LSP so far it's been Snappy I
mean it's been faster than what I
remember viim doing that is totally
anecdotal I don't I can't tell you that
that's actually true um uh but yeah so
uh you just able to change it cursor
explicitly you don't like it some people
don't like it and that's fine so
absolutely love the changing of the
cursor I do I love it because it's just
I I just I don't know why I love it
something else that I thought and this
is why I added neim the number one
reason I added neovim was to help me
from doing a bunch of typing and and
this is something that I have been
holding off on I honestly this is where
you could call me a boomer and you would
be right I was like I don't need no you
know file completion I don't need symbol
completion because you know I'm a
hacking I tell you what if you're a
developer you need completion
particularly today after the the
kubernetes code base has got 80
character you know you know complete
nobody wants to type that seriously if
you're trying to do a go if you're
trying to work with a ghost stand
library at all there are there are
identifiers in there that are 30
characters long nobody wants to type
that if you're typing that you probably
need to ask yourself why because
completion is pretty damn fast and I'm
still trying to get good with it I'm
still trying to get good with it so I do
insult uh you know and I just H tab tab
and usually it gets all the things that
I need uh and I get my thing I I always
I I don't I don't know why I do that I
do that I'm still trying to figure
completion out I've always been a huge
completion that I made Bonsai so that I
can have better command line completion
for my tools why would I not want
completion in my scripts um I still also
have um this one I don't understand so
this one for some reason I have to go
down and back to it to get it to take
which is kind of weird anyway so uh one
of the things I do not like is I I
thought I was not going to like is the
popping up of like different options
while you're typing and and that it
doesn't bother me it doesn't bother me
not nearly as much as I thought it would
bother me so I I was wrong on that
that's totally fine uh yeah C tags is
great but it's only for C it cags is
only great for only I'm making a video
hi honey good to see you I'm just about
I I don't mean to I'll be right back my
wife's here so I got to close up this
video we're almost done uh bar block
indicates the insert mode uh we got that
l l instead of Bim script so let's
actually end on the single single
biggest reason
uh there's inspect too let's talk about
inspect and then we'll end on the
biggest one uh inspect lets you see
exactly what's going on I'm not in theim
so uh expect actually is is something I
actually wrote a CO a function in V Bim
script to do the same thing insect tells
you what your syntax stuff is so when
you're dealing with your syntax
overloads and stuff you know what you're
dealing with and I had to write a
function in Bim script to do that before
and it was pain because it wasn't it
wasn't it didn't always work that is one
of the best additions if you're writing
your own syntax additions and stuff like
that then you might oh thank you for
that um but you know if you're writing
your own additions to it um to something
you know you want to know what that you
want to customize your highlighting
inspect is ABS I probably should hotkey
it um but this is actually one of the
coolest things ever made because you can
actually do your own your own stuff
right so let let me show you what I mean
here you can do um V Marc so I've done a
bunch of customization to go with my
group box that it didn't you know didn't
quite work uh gosh Rob and um so you
know my my highlight commands right
where are they where are they um let me
see if I can find them here they are so
here's all my highlights and you know I
I couldn't always tell what the colors
are um I mean you guys probably know you
can do hi here and it'll show you all
your highlights and you can tell the
type but to to know what what syntax
you're on hovering over with the inspect
command this does not exist in V vim and
you this is perfect because it gives you
exactly the information you're trying to
get so you can do your customized uh
extensions to your own syntax it's
amazing it's it's a good reason to use
it uh almost a good reason all by itself
to use neim over Vim if you're okay with
it that almost is and if you're a guy
like me and the second but the single
most the progressive enhancement with
neim that's how you skip the stuff and
just have neim stuff in your B RC so you
have a single bmrc everywhere that is
important but the single biggest reason
I'm going to end on this before I go is
Lua and I with L all the time I used to
call Neo you know viim for Roblox
players uh that's actually based on an
interesting story I actually I have
nothing against Lu I joke all the time
about it's a great language it's the
most edable language ever made on by
humans is my opinion and Roblox was made
with it uh I used to teach a school and
we started teaching Roblox because they
could learn how to code in Roblox uh
until Roblox said if you're playing our
game and you're on Linux you get we were
going to ban you and I was like no no
more Roblox so I have bad feelings about
that CU Roblox was actually a really
cool game uh Lua plugins the last time
World of Warcraft people make all game
plugins and mods are always done in Lua
so Lua is kind of known as that thing
that you know modders learn and and but
to be fair the tibl software product
that I maintained at IBM uh also had L
embedding to do this extensions and
pandoc if you if you want to extend
pandoc to add a different syntax or
modify an existing syntax you can add
your own Lua plugins to pandoc which is
written in hasool so Lua is a solid
language Lua learning Lua will get a job
learning Vim script is never going to
get anybody a job Lil andc is a marriage
in heaven absolutely and you know and
that goes for python too right because
python is the best C stub language in
the world that's why all the AI people
do it because they can write C code and
fool them put it behind python they
never know tensorflow pytorch they're
all c pro that's all C by the way that's
all C python keeps getting all the
credit for all the AI stuff it's
actually C code that's got a layer on
top of it by python because that's what
academics do academics write really
complicated C code to to to you know do
fancy things and then they put a nice
happy python layer on top of it that's
what they've been doing forever and
they're just continuing to do it that's
why AI is dominated by python which is
really SE so then then you add but if
but L what I'm trying to say is that
anything with Lua integrates really well
with c and pretty much any Dynamic
including including go so it's got
bindings and lot it's a really great
anguage to learn you could actually get
paid to code in Lua all day you would
never get paid to code in Bim script all
day why is that in ADV Advantage because
if you have the opportunity to screw
around and learn Lua doing your personal
projects while you're screwing around
with new Bim and maybe you have a
baseline BM RC so that you're compatible
and you can use Bim anywhere right
probably a good I think you don't you
don't want you want to know enough Vim
to be able to read the vimrc file from
somebody else on a system or a copy
yours around so your Vim is productive
anywhere I still believe that that
doesn't mean you should learn B Merc
honestly you shouldn't it's it's
horrible you should spend that time
learning Lua and therefore before we
come to my final reason and it's the
biggest single reason to use Neo above
any other reason is that once you allow
yourself to have a standardized portable
of MRC now you can really go to town you
can have all kinds of fun making amazing
Lua plugins now that you know how to use
a Unix filter make sure you don't make a
plugin that can be better done from the
command line using a shell script
because then you could use a shell
script and other programs you can
combine them together in the Unix way
and do that but if you can find like a
syntax Plugin or some reason to do it
you have a lot of good examples and good
opportunity to learn Lua which will get
you a job so as you know I'm all about
helping people get jobs and maintain
jobs and upskilling that is my
fundamental reason for being it's the
reason I'm streaming and by say I'm
going to say without any you know regret
at all that neim will get you closer to
having uh will teach you more skills
that will get you a job assuming you
learn vimrc enough to do that then then
then Vim ever will
and and that's a fundamental change in
my position based on the fact it took I
was like you know you know since the VRC
is the only thing they really need to
learn there's nothing wrong with
learning Lua in fact Lu is way better
than bmrc and when I realized that I was
like damn neim is better for
beginners with one caveat that you learn
how to use a vmrc and you learn Vim
everywhere if you learn VMR ever SE
everywhere and you learn how to use if
you learn how to use Vim first and you
have a vmrc that'll go anywhere and
number two you know how to make a Unix
filter and use the Unix filter command
then go to town go to town learning Lua
and doing all the fun things that you
want to do in Lu and and in that sense
nein will actually do more for beginners
by helping them learn skills that are
actually profitable now you have to
decide whether you want to invest a ton
of time making a bunch of pretty new L
plugins instead of writing some go
Enterprise you know Cloud development
code or Java or python or anything
that's going to get you a job but but Lu
is at least not a wasted skill you know
that's what I'm trying to say you know
spending your time you know going
through the Vim script book like I have
I have the book you know it's a wasted
it's a completely wasted skill totally
wasted in 2024 what are you going to do
it for you know why why do you need it I
mean you know you first of all you don't
need half the stuff that you need to
write a MRC script for you just need
somebody to get you the Baseline one to
get it working in the first place and if
you know you're never ever ever going to
be on a system that's ever going to have
a MRC file I mean maybe you just learn
to use maybe you just learn to use bare
bones them with no modifications
whatsoever and then you just go to town
doing nothing but Lua and and that that
helps you have you now you have Lua
skills you're you're going to bloat your
neovim and that's up to you to decide if
you want to do people who don't like
neovim don't like me saying this stuff
because they're like no that thing they
waited all they they joke about how all
the latency from Tre sitter and things
like that and they're not wrong I mean
you know you you can make neim as slow
as BS code if you want and I'm not
saying I'm not saying don't do it but
you know there might be a better way to
spend your time that's all I'm saying uh
so so I can use my vmrc as as input in
absolutely so let me let me just end one
on on that so the reason that I I the
main reason I I changed my tune is that
they I was so mad that they wouldn't
read my bmrc where I put it but then
somebody showed me this this is all you
need you just need to put this in your
config envm init.vim and this could be
Lua I tried to Port this to Lu and
everything fell apart because I don't
Lua that well um I I probably would do
this in Lua if I were to do it because
because all the all the plugins and
everything is always written in Lua in
NE OBM community so I would probably use
an init.lua here if you know how to do
that why do you care because this file
only exists on a system that has Neo
installed period And so and then you you
you you saw my bash RC right I already
showed you this but my bash RC
progressively adds support for Vim um
depending on what it detects on the
system so if it has Vim on the system
then my my my VI my fingers open Bim if
I have neim on the system it opens neim
I'm using VI the whole time you can use
Bim if you want doesn't matter but the
point is is that is that I'm now opening
the thing that I want to do and I don't
even have to think about it I don't even
have to think about in fact in fact I
was doing the the zcast thing it was VI
it was vim and not de I couldn't even
tell the difference why because both of
them are using the same
vimrc so other than the screen key right
and the screen key is is is is sectioned
out by an if statement so so this is
been uh you know I mean this is this has
been a banner fish uh Neo let's see if
we can give a um yeah we can do the neim
thing uh I need to to Rel order the Bim
stuff yes really can big I mean and
that's that's up to you right so so once
again if you if you skipped all the way
to the end I hope you'll forgive me for
being uh just plain mean uh about it um
the reason that I was mean about it was
because I I felt like I was on the
defensive because so many people were
saying some really horrible things about
me because I refused to get on board
with neim and that pissed me off and so
it became a little bit of a war uh and I
don't like that that happened I wish I
had had a thicker skin and had been able
to uh do my own research which I did
originally I was I was really much more
kind in the beginning and then I I
really got jaded because people were
just letting go man they were they were
making all kinds of attacks if you read
that Reddit thread you'll see it I mean
it's it's just it's just the internet
you know at its worst um making no no
sense at all there was no objective
there were no um no objective uh
evaluations about it it was just all
attack the old guy and and I was like
[__] you I was so pissed off that at
that point I was like the next rust
person or neoen person who comes in my
chat who says why aren't you using
neovim I would rip him a new one because
I would assume that they were just like
all the other
[__] and that's wrong
that's wrong and quite
frankly all of us need to stop doing
that whether whether it's neovim or rust
or or who you're going to Dr you're
going to vote for we have to start
assuming not the worst in people we have
to start asking ourselves why are they
doing it that way why did they rip smile
out you know what I mean um this morning
someone said that to them right so I'm
glad that you guys are confirming that
this is happening and and if you are
that person if you really love the thing
seek to understand before you Flex
please please do that and I'm pretty
sure I'm I'm guilty of flexing before I
sought to understand many times and that
is not a good thing and we are seeing
that that problem everywhere we're
seeing it in the in the rust in the
colonel conversation we're seeing it in
modern politics we're seeing it even on
Twitch streams and and it and it is
stupid it's absolutely stupid I mean
it's you know we disagree on a thing
okay great go use the other thing people
always tell me well why are you get B
out of shape just use a thing if you
don't like it just you don't use it I
said that's not that's not what's
triggering me what's triggering me is
the entire the entire thread of people
attacking my character and personality
and appearance that's what's Tri
triggering
me all right uh why not Russ but why go
why not JS but ybs go yeah so uh people
get militant about everything and you
know and so you know people frequently
it's funny because a lot of people will
critique me using the same thing I'm
saying they would say why don't you just
not use it if you don't like it and just
shut your mouth and the reason is
because of the all the other people who
open their
mouth and not not just to say why they
prefer their thing but to attack
everybody else and quite frankly I think
we need people who disagree and who need
to say why they disagree and if we don't
have that we lose Prime himself just
just quoted he he quoted he was quoting
T balds and reading about some stuff and
talking about the toxicity over there
but he did praise the fact that they
have really healthy arguments over I
don't think they're healthy but they
have arguments over there and they would
they would arrive at a conclusion that
was better and the fact that they were
these these heated
disagreements are good we get a better
product out of it that way as long as it
doesn't paralyze the product so a
disagreement in doing things a different
way and saying I'm not doing it that way
don't get mad you're busy that's good
for the world what's not good for the
world is is AD hominum and and making
fun of somebody for their bouncy ball U
or which is I just think it's cute now I
do I honestly do I got no I got no
negativity about that you know so um so
I'm going to go now uh that was a very
long video uh I a lot of you aren't
going to make it through the whole thing
but that is the only thing every
anything negative in my in my zle
casting about neim has been banished and
removed and um only only the positive
things remain uh anything that I
actually have that's a legitimate
negative about neim will show up as an
issue in the neim project and I will
actually open an issue or look for one
and say hey why did this thing die here
why did this thing why you know why
aren't you using the the cash directory
the way you're supposed to uh instead of
using you know local state that is going
to be a bug I'm actually going to open
that bug on the neoen project because I
do contrary to what everything might
every might think about me I actually
want to see the neoen project succeed I
really do I sincerely do and that's the
end of that one you like my Turnal
that's just ask you term yeah all right
everybody that's the end of that video
and I'm going to start that upload and I
don't know if I'm going to be able to
come back I am going to take a few
minutes to go check the base with my
wife and then when we come back maybe
we'll do some go coding all right